Vose Galleries of Boston
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Vose Galleries of Boston records
circa 1876, 1890s-1996
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Vose Galleries of Boston
25.6 linear feet
The records of Vose Galleries of Boston measure 25.6 linear feet and date from circa 1876, 1890s-1996 with the bulk of materials dating from 1920s-1930s. Nearly 90 percent of the collection documents the gallery's handling of American paintings and portraits through incoming and outgoing business correspondence with artists, clients, galleries, and museums, including considerable correspondence with portrait artist Alfred Jonniaux and clients regarding commissioned portraits. Other materials include client files; artists' biographies; records of sales, consignments, framing, restoration, and banking, mostly from the 1940s-1960s; and scattered exhibition catalogs, newspaper clippings, and postcards. Also found is a handwritten manuscript regarding the 1876 Centennial Exhibition in Philadelphia, PA and a 1991 videotape about the Vose Galleries and its founding family.
Provenance
The Vose Galleries of Boston records were donated in several installments from 1974 to 1997 by Robert C. Vose, Jr.
Separated Material
From 1965-1994, Vose Galleries of Boston loaned materials to the Archives of American Art for microfilming which are available on microfilm reels B1, 2380, 3936-3940, 4593-4594, and 4909 and by interlibrary loan. These materials were returned after microfilming and not included in later donations from the gallery. Briefly described below, the materials are not included in the container listing of this finding aid.
Reel B1 contains a scrapbook compiled by Seth Vose and annotated by Robert Vose that contains clippings, 1886-1900, and an 1889 letter from author and critic Alfred Trumble; and a scrapbook compiled and annotated by Robert C. Vose spanning the years 1920-1940, 1897, and 1905, and containing clippings and handwritten lists.
Reel 2380 contains numerous photographs, circa 1890-1964, of Seth Morton Vose, Robert C. Vose, Sr., artists, collectors, and dealers associated with Vose Galleries; a Macbeth Gallery "smoker" in honor of Emil Carlsen; a drawing of Charles Emil Heil by George F. Wing, and a charcoal drawing after Monticelli by Albion Harris Bicknell. Many of the photographs are annotated by Robert C. Vose.
Reels 3936-3940 contain account books, 1871-1887; a journal, 1889-1903, a ledger, 1889-1901; invoice books, 1896-circa 1954, inventories of paintings and drawings in stock, 1884, 1892 and 1906; exhibition records, 1911-1982?; traveling exhibition records, 1915-1949; and a record of paintings sold, 1876-1894. Written permission is required to access these reels.
Reels 4593-4594 contain clippings, undated and 1891-1989, chiefly about purchases, sales and exhibitions, but also pertaining to art dealers, museums, artists, and art events.
Reel 4909 contains a scrapbook of clippings, announcements, programs, and other printed materials, 1882-1993.
Related Material
The Archives of American Art holds several separately cataloged collections related to Vose Galleries of Boston, including the Carrig-Rohane Shop records (1903-1962); oral history interviews with Seth Morton Vose (July 24, 1986 - April 28, 1987) and Robert C. Vose, Jr. (June 27 - July 23, 1986); a sound recording and videotape of a Robert C. Vose, Jr. lecture at the Somerset Club (May 14, 1987); a sound recording of an interview with Robert C. Vose (March 1961); the Miscellaneous Art Exhibition Catalog collection containing Vose Galleries exhibition catalogs, circa 1900-1941; and, Robert C. Vose, Jr. typescripts and clippings, 1961, on microfilm reels 3480 and 4314.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Historical Note
Vose Galleries is a long time family run art gallery based in the Boston, Mass. area.
In 1841, Joseph Vose purchased Westminster Art Gallery, a small Providence, Rhode Island art gallery founded by Ransom Hicks. At the age of 19 in 1850, Joseph's son Seth Morton Vose joined the gallery and five years later became director. The gallery's primary business until the late 1860s was frame making, gilding and art supplies. Seth Morton Vose had a passion for art, especially the French painters of the Barbizon School and he slowly began buying and exhibiting artwork. By 1882, the gallery regularly exhibited in Boston.
Seth's son Robert C. Vose joined the business in 1896, and managed the gallery's Boston office from 1897. Robert broadened the gallery's horizons by showing his fine stock of Barbizon, Dutch, English and American artists throughout America, while his younger brother, Nathaniel, and his cousin, Charles Thompson, handled the Boston gallery. During the next sixty-seven years, Robert C. Vose moved the gallery into a position of national prominence.
In 1924, Nathaniel left the gallery and established his own gallery in Providence. The Boston gallery's name changed to Robert C. Vose Galleries, and around the same time, took over the Carrig-Rohane framing company. In 1931-1932, Robert's three sons, Robert C. Vose, Jr., Seth Morton Vose II, and Herbert Vose, joined the firm. The gallery continued to show exhibitions in Boston, and the sons took turns joining their father on the road. The gallery's name was changed to Vose Galleries of Boston, Inc. in 1952. In 1963, Vose Galleries moved to their current location at 238 Newbury Street in Boston. Robert C. Vose passed away in 1964.
Robert C. Vose, Jr.'s sons, Abbot W. Vose and Robert C. Vose III, joined the gallery in 1968 and 1970, respectively. Robert C. Vose, Jr. passed away in 1998. The Vose Galleries of Boston continues to operate at Newbury Street under the direction of the sixth generation of the Vose family.
Scope and Content Note
The records of Vose Galleries of Boston measure 25.6 linear feet and date from circa 1876, 1890s-1996 with the bulk of materials dating from 1920s-1930s. Nearly 90 percent of the collection documents the gallery's handling of American paintings and portraits through incoming and outgoing business correspondence with artists, clients, galleries, and museums, including considerable correspondence with portrait artist Alfred Jonniaux and clients regarding commissioned portraits. Other materials include client files; artists' biographies; records of sales, consignments, framing, restoration, and banking, mostly from the 1940s-1960s; and scattered exhibition catalogs, newspaper clippings, and postcards. Also found is a handwritten manuscript regarding the 1876 Centennial Exhibition in Philadelphia, PA and a 1991 videotape about the Vose Galleries and its founding family.
Correspondence of note is with artists Childe Hassam, Malvina Hoffman, Alfred Jonniaux, and John Singer Sargent; galleries Ehrich Galleries, Clapp & Graham Co., M. Knoedler & Co., Macbeth Galleries, Milch Galleries, Newhouse Galleries, Arthur U. Newton Galleries, Norton Galleries, and Howard Young Galleries; the estates of Anna Coleman Ladd and William E. Norton; and the family of Abbott H. Thayer.
Researchers should note that the records do not comprehensively span the gallery's history or operations. The bulk of the collection is correspondence from Robert C. Vose's era running the Robert C. Vose Galleries in the 1920s-1930s and, lesser so, under Robert C. Vose, Jr.'s direction in the 1970s. There is little material in the collection which dates before the 1910s or the 1950s-1960s, other than correspondence regarding Alfred Jonniaux and some financial records. There is a handful of correspondence which covers the period of R.C. & N.M. Vose Gallery. Records loaned for microfilming should be consulted for materials outside of the bulk dates of this collection, especially for materials from the late 1800s-early 1900s.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 5 series:
Series 1: Correspondence, 1895-1996 (Boxes 1-23; 22.6 linear feet)
Series 2: Customer Files, 1912-1946 (Boxes 23-24; 0.8 linear feet)
Series 3: Art-Related Files, circa 1876, 1890s-1947 (Box 24; 7 folders)
Series 4: Financial Records, 1911-1962, 1991 (Boxes 24-25; 1.8 linear feet)
Series 5: Printed Materials, circa 1904-1990 (Boxes 25-26; 0.4 linear feet)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Ladd, Anna Coleman, 1878-1939; Norton, William E., 1843-1916; Thayer, Abbott Handerson, 1849-1921; R.C. & N.M. Vose (Firm); Robert C. Vose Galleries; Centennial Exhibition (1876: Philadelphia, Pa.)
Subjects-Topical:
Art, Modern--19th century--Massachusetts--Boston; Art, Modern--20th century--Massachusetts--Boston; Art dealers--Massachusetts--Boston; Art galleries, Commercial--Massachusetts--Boston; Art galleries, Commercial--Rhode Island--Providence; Artists--United States--Photographs; Picture frame industry--Massachusetts--Boston; Picture frames and framing
Types of Materials:
Manuscript; Video recordings
Names:
Hassam, Childe, 1859-1935; Hoffman, Malvina, 1887-1966; Jonniaux, Alfred, b. 1882; Sargent, John Singer, 1856-1925; Vose, Robert Churchill, 1873-; Vose, Robert C. (Robert Churchill), 1911-1998; Arthur U. Newton Galleries; Ehrich Galleries (New York, N.Y.); Howard Young Galleries (New York, N.Y.); Jill Newhouse (Gallery); M. Knoedler & Co.; Macbeth Gallery; Milch Galleries; Norton Gallery and School of Art
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Correspondence, 1895-1996, Series 1:; (Boxes 1-23; 22.6 linear feet)
  Correspondence contains incoming and outgoing business correspondence with artists, clients, galleries and museums, regarding consignments, sales, purchases, and exhibitions. The bulk of the correspondence dates from the 1920s-1930s and the 1970s, and was originally grouped by date ranges spanning a few years. Considerable correspondence with portrait artist Alfred Jonniaux and with clients regarding commissioned portraits dates from the 1950s to mid-1960s. Scattered exhibition catalogs, price lists and printed materials are also found throughout the series.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by name, geographical location, or subject; then chronologically. Generally, dates of "1947" and those from the 1980s-1990s indicate the inclusion of a handwritten note presumably by Robert C. Vose, Jr. regarding the date in which the file's contents were reviewed.
  - A File, circa 1917-1943, 1993, (10 folders) (Box 1, Folder 1-10)
  - Abbot, Edward M., 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Abbott, Holker, 1922-1924, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Arthur Ackerman & Son, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Addison Gallery of American Art, 1931, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The Adirondack Museum, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - [Advertising?], 1921-1926, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Advertising, 1931-1933, 1968, 1979-1981, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
  - Thos. Agnew & Sons, Inc., 1931-1933, 1971-1979, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
  - Ainslie Galleries, 1921-1924, 1931-1932, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
  - Albany Institute of History and Art, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Albright Art Gallery, 1920-1925, 1993, (See also "Buffalo") (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Albright, J.J., 1921-1925, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Allen, Emma A., 1923, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Lyman Allyn Museum, 1931, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Almy, William, 1930-1933 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Alumni Associations, 1929, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - American Art Association, 1921-1925, 1931-1933, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 30-31)
  - American Express, 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1921-1924, 1931-1933, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
  - American Railway Express, 1921-1924, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Ames, John S., 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Amherst College, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Anderson Galleries, Chicago, 1922-1925, 1931-1933, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 38-39)
  - Anderson Galleries, New York City, 1921-1925, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Anderson, Karl, 1923-1924, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Applications, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Arkell, Bartlett, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Armstrong, Charles D., 1920-1924, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Aronstann, George C., 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Art Dealers Association of America, 1967-1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Artists' Packing & Shipping Co., 1921-1925, 1931-1933, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  - (Massachusetts) Artists Travelling Exhibition, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Associated Appraisers, Inc., 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Atlanta Art Association and High Museum of Art, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Austin, Catherine, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - B File, 1912-1946, 1993, (12 folders) (Box 2, Folder 13-24)
  - Babcock Galleries [E.C. Babcock], 1926-1938, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
  - Bainter, Fay, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Ballou, Latimer, Mrs., 1923 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Ballou, Walter S., Mr. and Mrs., 1921-1924, 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Baltimore Museum of Art, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Barbizon House, 1935-1937, 1947, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Bartholomay, Henry, 1921-1924, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Barton, Emery H., 1921-1923, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Bates, Charles F., 1920-1924, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Beach & Sweet, Inc., 1920-1925, 1931-1933, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 35-36)
  - The Beard Art Galleries, 1916-1924, 1931-1933, 1993, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 37-40)
  - The Beard Art Galleries, 1926-1938, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Beers Bros. Co., Inc., 1919-1933, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Alfred Bell & Co. Ltd., 1925 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Biays, Tolley Allender, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bigelow, Edward A., 1920-1925, 1932-1933, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
  - The Biltmore Salon, 1927-1938, (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 8-11)
  - Birmingham Museum of Art, 1973-1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Blackburn, [Jonathan B.], 1917-1926, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Blakeslee Galleries, 1907-1914, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bodell, Joseph, 1931-1933 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Bolton, C.K., 1931, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Bolton, Theodore, 1922-1923, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Boomer, J. Robert, 1931-1933 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Booth, George, 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Borein, Edward, circa 1931 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Boston Museum of Fine Arts, 1931-1933, (See also "Museum of Fine Arts (Boston, MA)") (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Boston Museums, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Boswell, Peyton, 1920-1924, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - A.M. Bouwens, 1922-1937, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
  - Bowdoin College, 1973-1977 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Bowdoin Museum of Fine Arts, 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Brandriff, George K., 1932 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Braun, J.F., 1895, 1930-1933 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Brewitt, H. Taylor, 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Brigham, Clarence, 1931-1933 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Brooklyn Museum, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Brooks Memorial Art Gallery (Memphis, TN), 1934-1946 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Brown, Henry J., The Raeburn Gallery, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Brown University, 1931-1933 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Browne, Margaret Fitzhugh, 1931-1933, 1972-1974, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 36-37)
  - Bryan, John Stewart, 1931-1933 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - W.S. Budworth & Son, 1931-1933 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Buffalo [Albright Art Gallery], 1931-1933 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Buffalo [Albright-Knox Art Gallery], 1970-1977 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Burnap, Frank P., 1931-1933 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Butler Art Institute, 1929-1933, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 43-44)
  - C File, 1920-1946, 1993, (10 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-10)
  - Cable, Ben T., Mrs., 1924, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - California Palace of the Legion of Honor, 1930-1933, (See also "Palace of the Legion of Honor") (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - The Canajoharie Art Gallery, 1971-1976 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Eric Carlberg Galleries, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1921-1925, 1931-1933, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
  - Carnegie Institute Museum of Art, 1971-1977 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Carson, Pirie, Scott and Company, 1920-1924, 1931-1933, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
  - Carson, Tom, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Casson Galleries (Irving & Casson), 1921-1925, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - The Century Association, 1920-1921, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Chambers, Eunice, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Chauvenet, Louis, Mrs., 1921-1922, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - The Art Institute of Chicago, 1921-1924, 1931-1933, 1972-1979, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 25-26)
  - Christie's, 1973-1980 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Cincinnati Art Museum, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Cincinnati Museum Association, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - The Clapp & Graham Co., Inc., 1921-1938, 1993, (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 30-32)
  - Clark, William A., 1921-1923, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Clarke, John Louis, 1931-1933 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Clarkson, Robert, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - The Cleveland Museum of Art, 1921-1925, 1931-1933, 1972-1979, 1993, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - Colby College, 1972-1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - College Art Association, 1931-1933 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Collins, D., 1969-1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - [Columbus Gallery of Fine Arts] Columbus Art Association, 1921-1925, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Columbus Gallery of Fine Arts, 1931-1933 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The Concord Art Association, 1974-1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Coomaraswamy, Ananda, Dr., 1921-1924, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Critics, 1934-1937, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Cudney, Ralph, 1917-1927, 1935-1937 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Currier & Ives [Photocopy of Letter From Vose and Huxford, June 20, 1860], undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - The Currier Gallery of Art, 1972-1978 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Cutler, Betty, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - D File, 1913, 1921-1942, 1993, (6 folders) (Box 5, Folder 17-22)
  - Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, 1971-1979 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Dartmouth College, 1972-1976 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - De Cordova Museum, 1966-1980 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Dealers, Foreign, 1926-1929 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Dealers in Antiques, 1921-1929, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 27-28)
  - Dealers in Paintings, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - The Denver Art Association, 1920-1925 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - The Denver Art Museum, 1971-1979 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - The Detroit Institute of Arts, 1921-1926, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Douglas, Frank E., 1929, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Dow, George Francis, 1928-1929, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Downes, William H., 1921-1925 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - T.D. Downing Company, 1928, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Dreicer & Co., 1929, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - du Pont Winterthur Museum, 1973-1980 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - A.J. Dunbar, 1928-1929, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Durham, Knowlton, 1921-1929 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Dyer, Anthony, 1929, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - E File, 1925-1945, 1993, undated, (5 folders) (Box 6, Folder 12-16)
  - Edeson Institute, 1936-1938 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - The Ehrich Galleries, 1915-1935, 1993, (5 folders) (Box 6, Folder 18-22)
  - El Paso Museum of Art, 1972-1979 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Elliott Exhibition - Mrs. J.W., 1925-1926 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - A.W. Elson & Company, 1924-1925 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Ely, Ruth, circa 1937, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Emery, Florence, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Enneking Estate, 1929-1934, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Erikson, Josiah, circa 1931-1938, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Evansville, Indiana (Society of Fine Arts and History), 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Everson Museum of Art, 1975-1979 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Exhibitions - Tentative, 1921-1924 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - F File, 1921-1943, 1993, (5 folders) (Box 6, Folder 33-37)
  - Fall River Library, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Farjeon, Ballin & Co., 1934-1938 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Farnsworth Museum, 1973-1979 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Daniel H. Farr Company, 1928-1929, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Faunce, W.H.P. [Brown University], 1921-1925 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Fearon Galleries, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Fechin, Nicholai, 1924-1926 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Felin, Charles F., 1921-1926 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Field, Marshall, Mrs., 1927 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - The Findlay Art Galleries, 1922-1925 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Findlay Galleries, 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Fine Arts Society, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Fine Arts Society, Ltd., 1923-1926 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - The Hoefler-Fisher Company (Providence), 1923-1925 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Fisher, Walter, Mrs., 1928-1929, 1934-1938 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Fitch, Mary, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - The Flint Institute of Arts, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Fogg Museum, Harvard, 1921-1925, 1934-1937, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
  - Foote, Henry Wilder, circa 1930, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Fordyce, Holliday & White, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Fort Wayne Art School and Museum, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Fort Worth [Amon Carter Museum], 1972-1979 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Fort Worth, TX, 1936-1937 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Foster, Ben, 1911 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Fouke, P.B., 1928-1929 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Frazier, Frederic, 1935, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Frick Art Reference Library, 1922-1938, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 20-21)
  - Fridenberg, Robert, 1928-1929 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Frost & Reed, 1925-1938, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 23-24)
  - Fuller, Alvan T., 1922-1928 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Fuller, George (Family of), 1921-1924 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - G File, 1919-1940, 1993, (5 folders) (Box 7, Folder 27-31)
  - Gage, George E., 1921-1927, 1993, (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 32-35)
  - Gannett, T.B., Mrs., 1926-1936, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 36-37)
  - Geneological Societies, 1934-1938 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - J.J. Gillespie Company, 1924-1925 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Goodspeed's Book Shop, 1929, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - The Gordon Galleries, 1929, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - The Gorham Company, 1928-1929, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Grand Central Art Galleries, 1932-1937, 1947, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Graves, Abbott, 1932-1938, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Graves, Algernon, 1913-1920 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Greatorex, Arthur, 1927-1929, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 46-47)
  - Green, Theodore Francis, Senator, 1937-1938, 1947, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - H File, 1914-1941, 1947, 1993, (6 folders) (Box 7, Folder 49-54)
  - Haass, Julius, Mrs., 1926 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Hamlen, Paul, 1924-1926 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Hanna, John, 1929-1938, 1947, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
  - Harding, W.P.G. [Regarding Artwork of Chester Harding], 1928 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Harlow, McDonald & Company, 1929, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Harris, Edward M., Dr. (Estate of), 1923-1925 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Hassam, Childe, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - The Hayloft (Frank Camp), 1927-1929, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
  - Hazard, Arthur M., 1922-1929 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Healey, Sumner, 1929, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Heaton, J.C., 1934-1938, 1947, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - The John Herron Art Institute, 1917-1935, 1947, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 14-15)
  - Hershey Corporation, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Higgs, P. Jackson, 1929, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Hirschl & Adler Galleries, 1973-1980 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Hoffman, Malvina, 1937-1938, 1947, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Hogg, Ima [The Bayou Bend Collection, Museum of Fine Arts, Houston, TX], 1973-1978 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Hotels, 1921-1929, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
  - The Museum of Fine Arts of Houston, 1936-1937, 1947, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Hudnut, Alexander, 1923-1925 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - The J.L. Hudson Company, 1929, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Hunter Gallery, 1973-1978 (Box 8, Folder 26)